NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Files 6174/008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Beekman Downtown, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Agreement between Beekman Downtown Hospital and Registered Nurses' Association, with cover letter to members from local president; list of RN benefits
- Benjamin Rush Center, 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Contractual Agreement between Benjamin Rush Center and Benjamin Rush Employees United, NYSUT, AFT, AFL-CIO, 7/15/82-9/15/84; contractual proposal, 9/15/84-9/15/86; letter to NYSUT director of organizing John O'Leary, expressing concern that decertification would be attempted because of high turnover in local leadership and uncertainty about ownership, March 9, 1984
- Benedictine United Nurses Society (BUNS) Members, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Correspondence from Lynn Duggan, Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals; organizing flyers; hospital financial statement (Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax), 1983 and 1985; mailing labels
- Benedictine Election, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Dues checks and representation cards; letters from management; hospital grievance appeals procedure; hospital financial statement (Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax), 1982
- Booth Memorial, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Brookhaven Memorial Hospital Medical Center, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Organizing flyers; list of organizing committee members; NLRB tally of ballots for FNHP, NYS Nurses Association, and Teamsters, August 4, 1988
- Brooklyn Hospital, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Hospital brochures for nurses, patients, and general audiences
- Brooklyn Visiting Nurse Service, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Brochures for Visiting Nurse Association of Brooklyn, Inc.; health and dental care benefits summary; newsletter
- Broome/Wilson, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Brochure by Broome United Nurses Association (FNHP), "Union Dues and Union Membership: The Truth of the Matter"; BUNA newsletter; memo to NYSUT director of organizing John O'Leary re Wilson Hospital organizing, January 10, 1983; organizing flyers; anti-union flyers by Hospital Employees Against Labor Trouble Here (HEALTH); FNHP glossy brochure; authorization cards; newspaper clippings; NLRB decision and direction of election, September 23, 1986
- Catholic Medical Center (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Nurse recruitment brochure for the Catholic Medical Center of Brooklyn and Queens, Inc.; letter from personnel department as follow-up to job fair
- Calvary Hospital (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Nurse recruitment brochure
- Cabrini Medical Center, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Agreement between Cabrini Medical Center and NYS Nurses Association, January 1, 1980- January 1, 1983; handwritten list of staff; organizing flyers for FNHP/NYSUT; letters from NYS Nurses Association; notice to Cabrini president of intent to organize by Federation of Nurses/UFT; organizing report form
- Clarkstown R.N., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Correspondence re Improper Practice Charge
- Cobleskill, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Telephone book for Cobleskill area, 1986-87; authorization cards for FNHP; letter from management of Community Hospital of Schoharie County re authorization cards, September 22; 1986; letter from a switchboard operator requesting that her card be returned and her name taken off any list, for fear of losing her job, October 9, 1986; FNHP fact sheet re authorization cards; handwritten list of employees; floppy disk; financial statements/annual reports for charitable organization, 1983-85
- Cornwall Hospital, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Financial statements/annual reports for charitable organization, 1978-82; organizing report form; photos of Cornwall Hospital exterior; FNHP brochures; correspondence; handwritten list of employees
- Champlain Valley Physicians Hospital Employees United, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Handwritten phone survey report; newspaper special supplement to Press-Republican re nursing at CVHP Plattsburgh; brochures and other organizing materials; letter to management re anti-union activity
- Communication Workers of America, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  White Collar Report article re end of strike by CWA nurses at Buffalo General Hospital
- Danbury Hospital, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Agreement between the Danbury Hospital and Danbury Hospital Professional Nurses' Association #47, FNHP, CSFT, AFT, AFL-CIO, July 1, 1983, and June 30, 1985; list of Danbury Hospital Career Opportunities; folder re organizing campaign materials
- Doctors Hospital, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Recruiting brochures for nurses; print ad
- Ellis Hospital, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  White Collar Report article re NYS Nurses' Association ratification of contract with Ellis Hospital
- Glens Falls Hospital Nurses Association, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Organizing materials; correspondence
- Health and Hospitals Corp. Nursing (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Organizing materials for Federation of Nurses/UFT against 1199; correspondence re NYS Office of Collective Bargaining decision re management/confidential employees; job description for nurse supervisor position
- Highland Hospital, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Ad for weekend nurses at Highland Hospital, Rochester, touting pay, June 12, 1988; newspaper clipping re decertification of union at Highland Hospital, July 27, 1983; newspaper clipping re creation of for-profit corporation at Highland Hospital, September 28, 1984
- Home Care Agency, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Brochures for home health care/temporary staffing agencies, aimed at nurses, hospitals, and patients; annual report for the Olsten Corporation
- Humana (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Folder with recruiting materials for Humana Mobile Nurse Corps
- Hempstead (Box 6, Folder 26)
  Nursing recruiting brochure
- Interfaith Medical Center, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Patient Guide; newsletter, Together, from Dept. of Human Resources; recruiting brochure, "A New Health-Care Resource Grows in Brooklyn"
- Jefferson Rehabilitation Center, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Horizon, official newsletter of the Jefferson Rehabilitation Center Employees Rights Union (NYSUT); NLRB Tally of Ballots; list of arguments used by Jefferson Rehabilitation Center against NYSUT in the 1985 campaign; letter from management, August 20; brochure, "Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals AFT Services and Benefits for Members"; memo to organizers from NYSUT director of organizing John O'Leary recapping campaign, October 30; memorandum of opposition to proposed bill requiring a bachelor's degree for licensure for nursing, with attached text of legislation
- Lenox Hill, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Nursing recruitment brochure; hand-written letter to organizer Lynn Duggan from nurse re need for nurses to assert themselves and communicate, April 2, 1985; White Collar Report articles re Jamaica Hospital contract, certification of union at Lenox Hill Hospital, April 10, 1985; article re strike settlement at Lenox Hill, January 13, 1988
- Lutheran Medical Center, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Nurse recruitment brochure; agreement between Lutheran Medical Center and Federation of Nurses/UFT, Local 2, FNHP/AFT, AFL-CIO covering Registered Nurses, 1983-1986; contract summary; salary sheet; glossy booklet, "You and the UFT: A Handbook for Members of the United Federation of Teachers"; press release, UFT News, "Lutheran Nurses Approve Pact: Record Gains in Working Conditions, Salary," March 3, 1988
- Jamestown General, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Reporting forms documenting inadequate staffing; An Overview of NYSUT Services/Programs Prepared for the Jamestown General Hospital Nurses Association; announcement, Nurses Vote FNHP/NYSUT
- Kingsbrook Jewish Medical Center, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Recruitment brochure; White Collar Report article re NYS Nurses Association strike at Brooklyn Hospital, ratification of contract at Mt. Sinai
- Lawrence Hospital, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  Personnel Planning Checklist, including personal planning checklist; description of dental plan; nurse recruitment card for Lawrence Hospital, Bronxville, NY
- Lawrence and Memorial Hospital, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  Handwritten notes (mostly list of names and contact information) re Connecticut AFT RNs Unit 22
- Long Island College Hospital, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Annual Report of Charitable Organization (financial summary) for Long Island Jewish Medical Center, 1984-86; recruitment flyer (benefits sheet) for the Long Island College Hospital Division of Nursing; recruitment flyer for FNHP/NYSUT; form letter from director of nurse recruitment, November 13, 1984
- Maimonides (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Article in Labor Relations Week re ratification of two-year contract between Maimonides Medical Center in Brooklyn and NYS Nurses Association
- Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Recruiting brochures; newsletter, Nursing Highlights
- Methodist Hospital, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Agreement between Methodist Hospital of Brooklyn and the New York State Nurses Association, February 15, 1983-February 15, 1986; nurse recruitment brochure
- New Rochelle Hospital (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Nurse recruitment brochure; flyer for open house
- Misericordia Hospital/Our Lady of Mercy, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Institutional analysis of Misericordia Hospital, by NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, focusing on financial information derived from filings with the NYS Department of Health, Internal Revenue Service, and other agencies, for use by organizers; fact sheet; recruiting brochure for Our Lady of Mercy Medical Center, Bronx; organizing materials, including authorization card, by Federation of Nurses/UFT; handwritten list of contacts